SIDDHARTHSAMANTA

FRONTEND DEVELOPER I DESIGNER I PROGRAMMER

VARANASI, UTTAR PRADESH

7007454645

93siddhartha@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

Problem Solver and fast learner with strong communication skills. I am motivated to upgrade and expand my skill set. Passionate Front-End Developer and Designer with experience in blending the art of design and skill of programming to deliver an immersive and engaging user experience through efficient website designing and development.

TECHNICAL SKILL

ReactJS C/C++
Figma JavaScript

HTML & CSS Adobe Photoshop
Python Adobe AfterEffects

PROFILES

 \mathbf{O}

cyber-sid



93siddhartha



siddharthsamanta

ACHIEVEMENTS

EDUCATION

UG | B.Tech, Computer Science and Engineering

Ajay Kumar Garg Engineering College 2019 - 23

- Maintained a SGPA of 8.5

Higher Secondary School

Sunbeam Varuna 2016 - 18 - Class XII , 84%

- Class X, 9.6 CGPA

5 Secured Zhan

- Secured 2nd Prize in Scrolls'19.
- 5 Star in HackerRank in C++.
- Achieved international rank 3945 in Google Hashcode.

WORK EXPERIENCE

UI/UX Designer

Photoshooto Aug 2021-Sep 2021

- Designed a Product based website.
- Prototyped the website and connected all the pages and components in UI.

Frontend Developer

Parakh Online Pvt. Ltd.

Aug 2022-Sep 2022

- Developed different product based screens
- Performed Proof of Concept (POC)
- Created website for student and teacher with different functionalities.

PROJECTS

Movie Application Design (Link)

Tech: Figma

- A movie browser for Mobile
- Designed UI and UX of the movie app with all its features.

Investment Website Design (Link)

Tech: Figma

- An Investment Website
- Designed UI of the investment website with all its features and different plans.

Online Grocery Shopping (Link)

Tech: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

- A fully responsive website for shopping of groceries online
- You can add, remove and manage your cart in the website

Anime Recommendation with watch links (Link)

Tech: ReactJs

- It is a website with different anime options.
- Clicking on the watch now redirects users to the site where user can watch the anime.

Amazon Clone (Link)

Tech: ReactJs,Firebase

- An Amazon website with Login, Add to Cart and Remove to Cart functions
- The Backend data is stored in Firebase.
- User can login and signup using Firebase authentication.